{
  "title": "Consultants / Structural Engineer Exam - Part 1",
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "The poisson's Ratio for structural steel is",
      "options": {
        "A": "0.2",
        "B": "0.4",
        "C": "0.5",
        "D": "0.3"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "As per DM rules the minimum additional loads to be taken from sides for design shoring is KN/m2",
      "options": {
        "A": "15",
        "B": "10",
        "C": "25",
        "D": "20"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "What is the maximum vertical deflection for cantilever steel structural as per BS 5950",
      "options": {
        "A": "L/360",
        "B": "L/200",
        "C": "L/100",
        "D": "L/180"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "The effective length factor Ky for column with both ends pinned is",
      "options": {
        "A": "2",
        "B": "0.8",
        "C": "2.1",
        "D": "1"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "The Modulus of elasticity for structural steel is N/mm2",
      "options": {
        "A": "250,000",
        "B": "270,000",
        "C": "290,000",
        "D": "210,000"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "The yield strength of ASTM A36 steel is MPa",
      "options": {
        "A": "200",
        "B": "3600",
        "C": "36",
        "D": "250"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "The column with large radius of gyration is",
      "options": {
        "A": "easy to fail in buckling",
        "B": "easy to fail in crushing",
        "C": "hard to fail in buckling",
        "D": "no relation with buckling"
      },
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "If d is the distance between flange angles, the vertical stiffeners in plate girders are spaced not greater than",
      "options": {
        "A": "d",
        "B": "1.25d",
        "C": "1.75d",
        "D": "1.5d"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "The yield strength of ASTM A516 Grade 60 steel is N/mm2",
      "options": {
        "A": "200",
        "B": "250",
        "C": "516",
        "D": "265"
      },
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "When a large value of radius of gyration is not required then",
      "options": {
        "A": "Channels are placed back to back",
        "B": "channel flanges are kept outward",
        "C": "Channel flanges are kept inward",
        "D": "none of them"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "question": "As per DM rules, the average compressive stress under working loads shall not exceed of the design cube strength of the pile concrete at 28 days",
      "options": {
        "A": "20%",
        "B": "50%",
        "C": "35%",
        "D": "25%"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "Mechanical splice (min. 50d) may be used after demonstration to the site engineer that the splice can develop of the specified yield strength of the bars",
      "options": {
        "A": "50%",
        "B": "100%",
        "C": "150%",
        "D": "125%"
      },
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "The correct lapping location in beams of heavy load slab is",
      "options": {
        "A": "mid in top and bottom",
        "B": "middle in bottom and near support at top bars",
        "C": "extreme middle third in top and at support in bottom",
        "D": "anywhere"
      },
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "question": "The lap in the RCC column in 3 storey buildings is provided in",
      "options": {
        "A": "near slab",
        "B": "near bottom",
        "C": "extreme middle third",
        "D": "center"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "question": "In offshore projects, piles can be driven down to a maximum of meter",
      "options": {
        "A": "90m",
        "B": "100m",
        "C": "200",
        "D": "150m"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "question": "The maximum deflection for cantilever beam under uniformly distributed load is",
      "options": {
        "A": "PL3/48EI",
        "B": "PL3/3EI",
        "C": "wL2/2",
        "D": "WL4/8"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "question": "As per DM requirement, the modification factor for post tensioning slab is",
      "options": {
        "A": "0.35",
        "B": "0.25",
        "C": "0.7",
        "D": "0.5"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 18,
      "question": "As per DM requirements, the maximum angle of excavation is",
      "options": {
        "A": "30",
        "B": "35",
        "C": "45",
        "D": "40"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 19,
      "question": "As per DIN 1048 standards, water penetration at 28 days test should not exceed max of",
      "options": {
        "A": "5mm",
        "B": "7mm",
        "C": "15mm",
        "D": "10mm"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 20,
      "question": "As per ASTM C1202, the rapid chloride penetration at 28 days test for RCC piles should not exceed maximum of Coulombs",
      "options": {
        "A": "700",
        "B": "1500",
        "C": "1000",
        "D": "1200"
      },
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "id": 21,
      "question": "As per ACI 318-14 the maximum allowable of elongation in post tensioning tendons is",
      "options": {
        "A": "5%",
        "B": "3%",
        "C": "10%",
        "D": "7%"
      },
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "id": 22,
      "question": "If d is the depth of PT slab then maximum spacing for the pt tendons as per ACI 318-05 is",
      "options": {
        "A": "5d or 5ft",
        "B": "10d or 5ft",
        "C": "7d or 7ft",
        "D": "7d or 5ft"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 23,
      "question": "Which test is required for piles during construction",
      "options": {
        "A": "Dynamic test",
        "B": "sonic test",
        "C": "integrity test",
        "D": "All"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 24,
      "question": "The minimum diameter of spiral shear links used for piles steel as per DM rules is",
      "options": {
        "A": "6mm",
        "B": "8mm",
        "C": "10mm",
        "D": "12mm"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 25,
      "question": "The maximum acceptable settlement for the piles under working loads is",
      "options": {
        "A": "12mm",
        "B": "10mm",
        "C": "25mm",
        "D": "8mm"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    }
  ]
}
